YUAN-CHIA (CHARLES) KUO

9314 Cherry Hill Rd, Apt 922, College Park, MD 20740 yuanchia@umd.edu, (267) 474-1203, www.linkedin.com/in/yuankuo

SUMMARY

Researcher with 10+ years of inter-disciplinary experience spanning molecular biology, biophysics, and analytical chemistry. My research accomplishments include: elucidating the apoptosis mechanism through purified Hepatitis C virus core protein in vitro; and development of DNA vaccine of Dengue and West Nile viruses in BALB/c mice; and synthesis, targeting, purification, and imaging of antibody-conjugated nanoparticles in in vitro and in vivo tumor model in nude mice with potential magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) diagnostic and therapeutic utility. My strengths include: Leadership, self-motivated, organized, and teamwork with colleagues for creating ideas and problem solving.

SKILLS

Computer:

Laboratory: Mammalian Cell Culture, PCR, Adenoviral Vector Cloning - Amplification and Infection, Electroporation

> of DNA vaccine, ÄKTA HPLC, UV/Vis, Column Chromatography, Recombinant Protein Expression and Purification, Plasma Membrane Purification, ELISA, SDS-PAGE, Western Blotting, FACS, Fluorescence Spectroscopy, Microtome Tissue Cutting, Immunohistochemistry, Immunofluorescence, In vitro translation, In vivo Injection and Imaging, Animal Handling, Cytotoxic T Lymphocyte Release Assay, Nanoparticle Synthesis and Targeting, Drug Delivery, Microfluidics, Bioconjugation, Rheology, Light

Scattering, Confocal Microscopy, Transmission Electron Microscopy, Scanning Electron Microscopy

SigmaPlot, ImageJ, Photoshop, Matlab, MS Office suite, Network Management, Website edit/maintenance Languages: Proficient in Mandarin Chinese, English

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Ph.D. Student Jun 2009 – Present

University of Maryland – Department of Radiation Oncology, School of Medicine

- Complex Fluids and Nanomaterials Group, School of Engineering

Project: Designation of biocompatible nanoparticles as vector for the apeutic medical imaging carrier and treatment

- Developed and characterized nanoparticles formulated by various materials as desired drug carriers
- Functionalized nanoprobes with bioconjugation of ligand for targeting Head & Neck cancer tumor cells in vitro and evaluated the binding efficacy by Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) in vivo in nude mice
- Engineered Erythrocyte Ghost (Erythrosomes) or Nanoerythrosomes conjugated with anti-EGFR antibody as an economical, efficient, and large scale production of biocompatible drug delivery system
- Collaboration involving ATP encapsulation in Erythrosome for releasing improvement

Biology Research Specialist

Dec 2006 - Jun 2008

University of Pennsylvania – Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, School of Medicine

Project: Identification of the pathogenesis of the mosquito-borne Flavivirus disease and DNA vaccine development

- Established West Nile Virus Pathogenesis for serving in drug discovery program
- Analyzed the functionality of West Nile Virus & Dengue Virus DNA vaccine construct in 293 cells
- Developed and examined Novel DNA Vaccine in BALB/c mice for inducing broad immune response against all four serotypes of Dengue Virus and West Nile Virus

Microbiology Research Assistant

Sep 2003 – Jul 2005

National Taiwan University Hospital – Department of Pediatrics, Gastroenterology & Hepatology Group

Project: RBMY, A Male Germ Cell-Specific RNA-Binding Protein, Activated in Human Liver Cancers

- Manipulated the expression level of RBMY protein in transgenic mice
- Prepared frozen/formalin-fixed, paraffin-embedded liver tissue and evaluated expression with IHC/IFA
- Developed and optimized immuno-staining protocols for evaluating RBMY protein in human liver specimen

Master Thesis Aug 1999 - Jul 2001

National Taiwan University – Department of Microbiology in College of Medicine

Project: Effect of the Hepatitis C Virus Core Protein on the TNF Cytokine Superfamily-mediated Cellular Apoptosis in the Hepatoma cells

- Cloned and amplified HCV Core-inserted Adenoviral vector as material to establish the HCV model
- Evaluated the infected apoptosis pathway of HepG2 / Huh7 cell lines with HCV core protein
- Validated the activation of cytokines in T-cells via HCV Core expression by cell apoptosis assay

Laboratory Research Technician

Jul 1997 – Jun 1999

National Taiwan University – Department of Plant Pathology and Entomology

- Assayed the susceptibility of the honeybee, Apis mellifera and separated the colonies
- Management of lab equipment and maintenance of computers and network service

YC KUO, Page 1/2

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Bioengineering, School of Engineering

University of Maryland, College Park, MD

Honor: Hong Ji Distinguished Fellowship, 2008-2009

Goldhaber Award, 2014

M.S. in Biotechnology, School of Engineering and Applied Science

University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

M.S. in Microbiology, College of Medicine, Graduate Institute of Microbiology

Jun 2001

National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan

B.S. in Plant Pathology and Entomology, College of BioResources and Agriculture

Jun 1999

Dec 2006

Expected: May 2015

 $National\ Taiwan\ University,\ Taipei,\ Taiwan$

Honor: Presidential Award

LEADERSHIP / PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATION

Membership Director, National Taiwan University Alumni Association in the Washington-Baltimore Area	a 2013 – Present
Vice President, Great DC Area Taiwanese Student Association	2010 - 2011
Secretary, University of Pennsylvania Taiwan Student Association	2006 - 2007
Associate Member, American Association of Physicists in Medicine	2013 - 2014
Associate Member, American Society for Radiation Oncology	2012 - 2013
Associate Member, American Chemical Society	2012 - 2014

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistantship

Biology for Engineers LaboratoryProfessor: Dr. Helim Aranda-EspinozaFall 2009BiomaterialProfessor: Dr. Joonil SeogSpring 2010

Undergraduate Mentoring

Ariel Ash-Shakoor, Project: Synthesis of stable chitosan nanoparticle and characterization

2010 – 2012

Dao Huang, ASPIRE Award, Project: Development of nano-sized vesicle via microfluidic devices

2013 – 2014

PUBLICATION

- Yuan-Chia Kuo, Chiwei Hung, Rao P. Gullapalli, Su Xu, Jiachen Zhuo, Srinivasa R.Raghavan, and Warren D. D'Souza, "Liposomal Nanoprobes that Combine Anti-EGFR Antibodies and MRI Contrast Agents: Synthesis and In Vitro Characterization." RSC Advances 4 (2014) 33756–33764
- Janet Hsu, Daniel Serrano, Tridib Bhowmick, Kishan Kumar, Yang Shen, Yuan-Chia Kuo, Carmen Garnacho and Silvia Muro, "Enhanced endothelial delivery and biochemical effects of α-galactosidase by ICAM-1-targeted nanocarriers for Fabry disease." Journal of Controlled Release 149 (2011) 323–331
- Mathura P. Ramanathan, Yuan-Chia Kuo, Bernard H. Selling, Qianjun Li, Niranjan Y. Sardesai, J. Joseph Kim, and David B. Weiner, "Development of a novel DNA SynCon™ tetravalent dengue vaccine that elicits immune responses against four serotypes." Vaccine 27 (2009) 6444–6453
- Mathura P. Ramanathan, Michele A. Kutzler, Yuan-Chia Kuo, Jian Yan, Harrison Liu, Vidhi Shah, Amrit Bawa, Bernard Selling, Niranjan Y. Sardesai, J. Joseph Kim and David B. Weiner, "Coimmunization with an optimized IL15 plasmid adjuvant enhances humoral immunity via stimulating B cells induced by genetically engineered DNA vaccines expressing consensus JEV and WNV E DIII." Vaccine 27 (2009) 4370–4380

SELECTED Conference Oral Presentations:

- Yuan-Chia Kuo, Dao Huang, Hyuntaek Oh, Warren D. D'Souza, Srinivasa R. Raghavan. (2014) Colloidal properties of erythrosomes derived from red blood cells
 88th ACS Colloids and Surfaces 2014 Symposium, Philadelphia, PA
- Yuan-Chia Kuo, Chiwei Hung, Srinivasa R. Raghavan, Warren D. D'Souza. (2013) Imaging of Targeted Cancer Therapy using Multifunctional Liposomal Nanoprobes and MRI
 55th American Association of Physicists in Medicine (AAPM) Annual Meeting and Exhibition. Indianapolis, IN
- Yuan-Chia Kuo, Chiwei Hung, Warren D. D'Souza, Srinivasa R. Raghavan. (2013) Multifunctional Liposomal Nanoprobes for Monitoring the Treatment of Head and Neck Cancer by MRI 2013 Material Research Society (MRS) Spring Meeting. San Francisco, California